

senior software engineer / site reliability engineer

1699 Market Street San Francisco, CA 94103

+1 415 937 3151

chad@anyonecanedit.org https://linkedin.com/in/chadhorohoe

Profile

I bring a wide-ranging set of experiences that can aid nearly any organization--for-profit, non-profit, even government--as they aim to scale. I've built things for small teams of engineers in a single location and I've also served traffic to hundreds of millions of users across the globe.

## Experience

Senior Software Engineer, ASAPP, Inc; San Francisco, CA – 2018-2019

- Lead the successful migration from github.com to Github Enterprise for ~460 repositories
- Implemented vendor-provided intrusion detection system (IDS) in staging and production
- Crafted and gained approval for the company-wide AWS resource tagging policy
- Provided feedback and advice for infrastructure & architectural needs of engineering teams
- With security, transitioned all access from IAM Users to IAM Roles backed by Okta/SAML
- Provisioned new and documented existing infrastructure using Terraform

Senior Software Engineer, Wikimedia Foundation; San Francisco, CA - 2016-2018

- Lead design process for overhaul of software deployment infrastructure
- Maintain code review, version control, CI and deployment systems
- Deployed our application and dealt with production environment debugging and remediation
- Managed the Release Engineering team on an as-needed basis

Software Engineer, Wikimedia Foundation; Richmond, VA / San Francisco, CA - 2010-2016

- Managed code deployment processes and third party releases for our flagship software
- Developed components of core application layer infrastructure

Project Configuration Management Analyst, Capital One; Richmond, VA - 2009-2010

- Aided in code repository administration on Unix servers
- Implemented software branch management and branching strategies for client projects
- Processed daily code migrations from development to staging to production

Web Development / IT Security Intern, Department of IT; Richmond, VA - 2007-2008

- Granted/denied security access to end users as needed across a variety of systems -- Active Directory, z/OS mainframe, Oracle and MSSQL databases
- Gathered compliance data for internal audits for PCI
- Developed web content for the City of Richmond's Internet and intranet sites
- Built the benefit calculation app for the retirement program for full time employees
- Managed and supported installation of MediaWiki installation, including custom changes

Education

Virginia Commonwealth University; Richmond, VA - BS in Information Systems, 2012

Skills

Python, Git, Terraform/HCL, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, Puppet, bare metal, scaling, Redis, Elasticsearch, Mysql, Sqlite, Java, PHP, rsync

(references available upon request)